<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>λ-cube</title>
    <link>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/</link>
    <description>Recent content on λ-cube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-in</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 23:11:03 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>&#34;A category-theoretic description of a group ring&#34;</title>
      <link>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/posts/a-category-theoretic-definition-of-a-group-ring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 23:11:03 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/posts/a-category-theoretic-definition-of-a-group-ring/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   Mathematical objects can often be described in several ways, each description usually offering a different perspective and serving a different purpose.
 For example, group rings - the subject of this post - can be described in two very different ways. Given a group G and a ring R, one way to think of the group ring R[G] is as the space of functions from G to R having finite support, with addition being pointwise and multiplication given by convolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing a function-finder tactic in Lean4</title>
      <link>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/posts/function-finder-tactic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 10:22:24 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/posts/function-finder-tactic/</guid>
      <description>Introduction   The Lean theorem prover is one of several that supports constructing proofs using tactics - commands that allow users to build up proofs step-by-step interactively at a high level of abstraction, usually interspersed with automation (for a demonstration of tactics and an introduction to Lean in general, consult the Natural Number Game). One of the appealing aspects of Lean, especially Lean4, is that there is a robust framework in place for users to write custom tactics within the language, making Lean its own metaprogramming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Post</title>
      <link>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/posts/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 19:17:30 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://0art0.github.io/lambda-cube/posts/test-post/</guid>
      <description>Some text.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
